A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Multimedia material, Accessions 2017:081 and 2017:084 FA1406
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Multimedia material, Accessions 2017:081 and 2017:084
1962-2015
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA1406
7.11 Cubic Feet 17 boxes (14 letter document containers, 2 legal document containers, and 1 16x20 oversize box)
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
Series 1: Project Photographs and Foundation-Assigned Photograph Commissions
Series 2: Office of Communications – General Photographs
Subseries 1: Susan V. Berresford Photographs
Subseries 2: Vice President Photographs
Subseries 3: Staff Photographs
Subseries 4: Building and Garden Photographs
Subseries 5: Trustees Photographs
Subseries 6: Filler Photographs
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2017 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accession 2017:081 and Accession 2017:084.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation was chartered by Henry and Edsel Ford in 1936 "to receive and administer funds for scientific, educational and charitable purposes, all for the public welfare", and initially served the Ford family's charitable interests in the Detroit area. Following the deaths of Edsel Ford (1943) and Henry Ford (1947), the Foundation was propelled to the forefront of philanthropy as the largest American foundation in terms of both endowment and yearly expenditures, and with an international scope to its major program areas.
During the Foundation's first twenty years its major programs were in international economic development, primary and higher education, educational and public broadcasting, behavioral sciences, civil liberties, urban development, fine arts and the humanities. The Ford Foundation also partnered with the Rockefeller Foundation in supporting agricultural development in South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia. Since the 1970s, the Foundation has also pioneered programs in women's rights, energy policy, micro-financing in under-developed countries, establishing human rights groups, and improving international HIV/AIDS education.
The Foundation's efforts in the field of communications have focused primarily on clarifying policy issues, advancing competence in journalism, and improving the system of public broadcasting in the United States. The Foundation's work in communications also aims to convey the lessons learned from its work and to counter the notion that societal problems are intractable.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains prints, negatives, transparencies, slides, and contact sheets that document Ford Foundation projects around the world as well as headshots of staff, executive officers, and trustees for the Ford Foundation's Office of Communications. Many photographs appear in annual reports and other Ford Foundation publications and promotional materials.
Related Materials
Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Photographic Collection, No. 1300-1356
AIDS (Disease) -- Developing Countries; Agricultural education; Arts, African; Colombia; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation -- China; Ford Foundation -- Egypt; Ghana and the Ford Foundation; Human rights; Photographs; Theater; Uganda
- Project Photographs and Foundation-Assigned Photograph Commissions, 1971-2014; 1
  - Zanzibar - Jozani Forest Project/CARE - Photos: Wendy Stone, circa 2004; Slides (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Slide pages: Jozani Forest Project/CARE #990-0130 Micro-Credit Programs; Mangrove, Zanzibar, Jozani Forest; Association of Non-Governmental Organization of Zanzibar; Taken by Wendy Stone
  - HIV/AIDS - All Projects - Photos: Wendy Stone, 2014 March 14; Slides (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Photos by Wendy Stone and Mary Ann (?); Includes Slums Information Development and Resource Centers Youth in Theatre; Family Planning Private Sector (FPPS) program - Kenyan Network of Women with AIDS (KENWA), and Herbal Medicine
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted - Open in 2024
  - Slums, Nairobi, Kenya - Health Care, AIDS Education, Schools - Photos: Wendy Stone, 1997-1999; Slides (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    Photos by Wendy Stone; 1997 Clean Up the World Day; Programs and projects funded by non-profit organizations like the Ford Foundation; Kibera Community Self-Help Schools, Kibera; Slums Information Development and Resource Centers (SIDAREC) - Pumwani - Clean Up the World; Kabiro Health Care Trust - Kawangware; Africa Foundations Learning Group (Dandora - Clean-Up); Straight Talk Newsletter for Teens
  - 1337 Annual Report 2000 (Kenya); Kibale Forest Coffee Project (Uganda), Assets/Environment and Development - Photos: Wendy Stone/Liaison, Slides (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Titles from slide pages: Kibale Forest Coffee Project; African Conservation Centre - Shampole Group Ranches; Community Conservation - Tanzania; Ecosystem Management Programs - Kajiaoo, Kenya; Kibale Tea Plantations; Management of Woodland Resources, Uganda Makerere Forestry Department
    Titles from original folder: Ford Foundation Nick's Projects - 1. Elangata Wuas Ecosystem Management Project, Kajiado; 2. Makers University Forestry Department, Uganda; 3. Kibale Coffee Project - Uganda; 4. Community Conservation Service Center - Arusha (Majai); 5. Kenya Women's Finance Trust (Mombana (sp?)); 6. Shampole Group Ranches Maasai Cattle Market
  - Refugee Law Project, Uganda; Kituo Cha Katiba, Uganda; Kenya Women's Finance Trust - Photos: Wendy Stone, 2000; Slides (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Photos: Wendy Stone; Notes from slide pages - East African Centre for Constitutional Development - 1339 Annual Report 2000 (Kenya) Kituo Cha Katiba (East Africa Centre for Constitutional Development) Peace and Social Justice (PSJ)/Governance; Uganda Law School; Refugee Law Project, Uganda - 1338 Annual Report 2000 (Kenya) Makerere University Refugee Law Project - Peace and Social Justice (PSJ)/Human Rights; Akiwa Mama Wa Africa - African Women's Leadership Institute
  - 2004 Annual Report - Ghana - Photos: Wendy Stone, 2004-2005; Slides (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Ghana - Kente Cloth; 1521 AR2004 International Fellowships Program - Bibiana Bangpuore, Wa, Ghana, Photos: Wendy Stone/Corbis
  - Projects in Kenya, Uganda, Tanzania - Photos: Wendy Stone, undated; Slides (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
    Photos by Wendy Stone; Slide page labels: Shangilia Mtoto WA Africa - Rejoice Child of Africa, Nairobi, Kenya, Youth Group Working to Educate Children in Slum Communities on HIV/AIDS Through Theatre and Dance Performances; Kenya Voluntary Women Rehabilitation Centre (KVWRC) and Income Generation Projects; Nairobi Slum Life; Family Planning Private Sector (FPPS); Kibera Community Self-Help Project (KICOSHEP); FPPS - Kenyan Network of Women With AIDS (KENWA); Straight Talk - Uganda; Kenya Association of Professional Counsellors; Women Fighting AIDS in Kenya (WOFAK) #990-1040; AIDS/HIV Clinic; KICOSHEP, Kibera Slum; Straight Talk, Kampala, Uganda; HIV/AIDS All NGO Groups; Faraja Trust, Morogoro, Tanzania; FPPS/Puppets; Blood Testing for HIV/AIDS, Kenya (AMREF); WOFAK AIDS Orphans; KAPC Counselling; AIDS - Strengthening STD/HIV AIDS Control Program; Ford Foundation Annual Reports; Ford Foundation Funded Projects; Miscellaneous - Environmental Sustainability; Child Mortality
  - 1169A Annual Report 1997 China I, II - Peking University, Department of Sociology, China - Photos: Rhodri Jones/Panos, 1998 January; Prints and Contact Sheets (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Assets: Community and Resource Development
  - 1169B Annual Report 1997 China I, II - Qianxi Women's Federation, Heibei Province - Photos: Rhodri Jones/Panos, 1995-1997; Prints and Contact Sheets (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Peace and Social Justice
  - 1169C Annual Report 1997 China I, II - Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, Rural Development Institute - Photos: Rhodri Jones/Panos, Prints and Contact Sheets (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Assets
  - 1169D Annual Report 1997 China I, II - Dagong Zidi Xiaoxue (Migrants' Children Primary School) - Photos: Rhodri Jones/Panos, Prints, Contact Sheets, and Notes (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Includes Notes for Ford Foundation in China and Description of Films for Ford Foundation in China 1998, both by Rhodri Jones
  - 1361 Winter Report 2001 - Israeli Arabs Story - Photos: Thomas Hartwell, 2000-2001; Prints, Contact Sheets, Caption Information (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1388 IFP Meeting at Ford Foundation - Photos: Martin Dixon, 2001 January; Contact Sheet (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1390 Annual Report 2000 - Susan's Essay - Hanoi Agricultural Institute - Photos: Tran Thi Hoa, 2000-2001; Contact Sheets (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1396 Summer 2001 - Urban Superintendents Program, Education, Media, Arts and Culture (EMAC)/Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR) - Photos: Susan Gaetz, Slides and Slide Captions (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Slides of Joseph Vigil, special education specialist who ran a program called Side by Side
  - 1397 Fall Report 2001 - Medellin Poetry Festival, Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)/Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), Medellin, Colombia - Photos: Paul Smith/Panos Pictures, Contact Sheets (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1400 Susan Berresford Addresses International Fellowships Board - Photos: John Rae, 2001 September 24; Contact Sheets, Negatives, and Prints (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1401 PBS/Local News Event at Ford, Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)/Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), Medellin, Colombia - Photos: Hazel Hankin, 2001 September 25; Contact Sheets and Negatives (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1403 Leadership for a Changing World - Event at the Ford Foundation - Photos: Martin Dixon, 2001 October 25; Contact Sheets and Group Shot (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 1446 Spring Report 2002 - Gay Kids in Foster Care, Green Chimneys and Lambda Legal - Photos: Hazel Hankin, Prints, Photocopies, and Negatives (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Story did not run in magazine
  - 1461 Fall Report 2002 - Middle College Story, LaGuardia Community College - Photos: Philip Greenberg, Model Release Forms (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1489 Fall Report 2003 - Family Promise/Karen Olson, Knowledge, Creativity, Freedom (KCF)/Education, Sexuality, Religion (ESR) - Photos: Matthew Septimus, Includes Contact Sheets and Release Forms (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Matthew Septimus Photography - S02974 - Ford Foundation, FFR, Family Promise, 2003 July; CD (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Matthew Septimus Photography - S02975 - Ford Foundation, FFR, Family Promise, 2003 July; CD (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Matthew Septimus Photography - S02976 - Ford Foundation, FFR, Family Promise, 2003 July; CD (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Matthew Septimus Photography - S02977 - Ford Foundation, FFR, Family Promise, 2003 July; CD (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Matthew Septimus Photography - S02978 - Ford Foundation, FFR, Family Promise, 2003 July; CD (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Matthew Septimus Photography - S02979 - Ford Foundation, FFR, Family Promise, 2003 July; CD (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 1490 Ford Foundation Report Fall 2003 - Bernadette Brooten, Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom (KCF)/Education, Sexuality, and Religion (ESR) - Photographer Dennis Milbauer, 2003 August; Transparencies (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 1474 Annual Report 2002 - Middle College High School, Excel Program, LaGuardia College Students - Photos: Philip Greenberg, Prints and Release Forms (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Box Sheets/Transmittal Forms - Detailed Description of Items and Boxes in Photograph Record Series, 1990-2000 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Created by the Ford Foundation Office of Communications
  - 611 Historical Museum of Senegal - Photos: John Chiasson, 1983 December; Negatives, Slides, and Contact Sheets (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 1357 Annual Report 2000 - (Egypt) Institute of Diplomatic Studies - Peace and Social Justice (PSJ)/Governance - Photos: Randa Shaath (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Institute for Diplomatic Studies - Grant no: 0880-0282
  - 1358 Annual Report 2000 - (Egypt) Cultural Association Sweden-Egypt (CASE), Education, Media, Arts and Culture (EMAC)/Arts and Culture - Photos: Randa Shaath, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 1374 Annual Report 2000 - The Galilee Society - Peace and Social Justice (PSJ)/Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC) - Photos: Thomas Hartwell, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 1381 Annual Report 2000 - WAFRIC Inter Press Service (IPS) Zimbabwe - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) Religion, Society, Culture - Photos: Piers Benatar/Panos Pictures, Poor quality photocopies - photocopies of slides (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 1383 Annual Report 2000 - WAFRIC PROMETRA: Association for the Promotion of Traditional Medicine - Assets/Sexuality and Reproductive Health - Photos: Piers Benatar/Panos, 2000-2001; Photocopies of slides (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Slides to Return to Ping Chong, 1995-2005 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Three slides taken by Ping Chong, Muna Tseng, Beatriz Schiller, and Carol Rosegg: Slide 1: After Sorrow, La MaMa Etc.; Slide 2: Elephant Memories, Walker Arts Center; Slide 3: Nosferatu, La MaMa Etc.
  - Santiago Images - Brochure Pictures, 2006 Book, 40th Anniversary, Optical Disk: Ford Foundation - Santiago Images - Brochure Pictures, 2006 Book, 40th Anniversary (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Ford Foundation - Santiago Images - Brochure Pictures, 2006 Book, 40th Anniversary, CD-R (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Note from original post-it: "Ifaat, let me know if you need anything else. Regards, Amy"
  - Good Neighbor Grantee Photos - Child Life Line, Nairobi, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Photos of Unknown Origin, 1993-1997 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Captions on photos include: BRAC - irrigation; #40F Annual Report 1997 Jerusalem Liuk PSJ-HRIC p. 88 50%; Innovation - Philippines - Roll #3: Negative 18-44a and 1a-9a: Nutrition (supplemental feeding) at San Isidro Day Care Center, Binmaley; ID - Samuel Orozco at left, Delia Saldivar at right, Photo: Eric Paul Zamora; ID - Araceli Garcia, Photo Eric Paul Zamora; Summer/Fall 1995 Report - George Ozik - Indonesia Irrigation; Tharaka Family Helper project, Meru District, Kenya, Photo: Carolyn Watson/Christian Children's Fund; Briefly Noted p. 26; Dagoberto Reyes - "Memory Project"; #787 Innovating America: Alternatives to Incarceration - Atlanta, Photos by Rob Nelson; Ford Foundation Annual Report 1996, p. 86, top image, EMAC section; Parnessa C. Seele - Founder/CEO of the Balm in Gilead, Inc., Annual Report 1996; Ford Foundation Dhaka Photos from 1993 FFSRD; Women's Protest 1997; Spring Report 1996 - Bill Strickland, Pittsburgh Post-Gazette p. 12; ABCD Folder - Reproduction Pop Consil We Own (?); UP-Richard Howard, Youthbuild 1994 Annual Report
  - Estate of James Karales - Selma-to-Montgomery March - Print, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    Used for 2006 Annual Report cover, 2006 Annual Report timeline, and 2009 business cards
  - 1485 Fall Report 2001 - Theater of Oppressed/Augusto Boal, Brazil, Photos: Joao Ripper (Stock Turned Photo Shoot), Prints and Contact Sheets (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - #1 Spring 2004 Ford Foundation Report - MASUM - Frontlines, Indian Sex/Health Grantee (Box 5, Folder 40)
    Mahila Sarvangeen Utkarsh Mandal (MASUM)
  - 955 Womens World Vision, China - 1994 Annual Report - Photos: Gao Bo, Print (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - 1355 Annual Report 2000 (EGYPT) - The Culture & Free Thought Association (Palestine) - Assets/Community Development - Photos: Thomas Hartwell, 1999-2000; Prints, Contact Sheets, and Photocopies (Box 5, Folder 42)
    Grant No: 995-0802
  - 1419C Annual Report 2001 Cairo - New Civic Forum - Peace and Social Justice (PSJ)/Governance - Photos: Randa Shaath, Poor quality photocopies of two slides (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - 1426 Annual Report 2001 US - Academy for Educational Development - Assets/Sex and Reproductive Health - Photos: Tom Roster (Box 5, Folder 44)
    Two slides and one contact sheet related to Grant No: 0980-1367-1
  - 1345 Annual Report 2000 (China) - Qinghua University Consumer Rights Law Clinic - Peace and Social Justice (PSJ)/Human Rights - Photos: Yuan Wei, 2000-2001; Slides, Negatives, and Photocopies (Box 5, Folder 45)
    Foundation-Administered Project (2543)
  - 1440 Susan V. Berresford in China/Site Visit to State Family Planning Association - Photos: Li Zhongchao, 2002 January 15 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - 1422A&B Annual Report 2001 Kenya - Maj Na Ufansi (Assets/Community Development) and VIVID Features (Education, Media, and Culture (EMAC)/Media) - Photos: Wendy Stone/Getty Images/Corbis, Photocopy of Slides (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - 1412C Annual Report 2001 Nigeria-West Africa - The Fate Foundation - Assets/Economics Development - Photos: Slim Akeh, Prints (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - 1432 Annual Report 2001 - Russia - CIS Research Center on Forced Migration - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture/Higher Education, 2000-2002 (Box 17, Folder 194)
    Photos: Yuri Kozyrev/Panos; Includes contact sheets, negatives, email correspondence, and Recommendation for Grant/FAP Action paperwork, Grant No. - 980-0789-2
  - 1298A&B Shoots - Human Rights - Morris Carpenter/Panos Pictures - Peru and Chile - Annual Report 1999, Negatives (Box 6, Folder 49)
    1298A Peru - Human Rights National Coordinator - PSJ/Human Rights; 1298B Santiago - CCHPS: Chilean Corp. for AIDS Prevention - Assets/HDRH
  - Rural Poverty Prints and Slides, 1971-1992 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    Prints from Bangladesh, China, Nigeria, Senegal, and El Salvador; 80 slides from a presentation: Issues in Caribbean Development: The Women's View (includes a working script with narration for each individual slide) presented by The Caribbean Women's Features Syndicate/UNESCO/UNFPA/Women and Development Unit/UWI, Barbados, 1984
  - Photos from the Democratic Republic of the Congo - LeMoyne, School Consolidation, Webster County, and Girl in Window, Brooklyn, 2000-2005; Includes Prints and slide (Box 6, Folder 51)
    Democratic Republic of the Congo Photocopies of Prints, 2003-2005, copyright LeMoyne; 1519 Winter Ford Foundation Report 2005, School Consolidation, Webster County, Challenge WVA/Linda Martin, Photos: Steven Rubin; #2 Fall 2000 Israeli Arabs Story, PSJ/HRIC, Photo: Chris Reardon - 1 print; Girl in Window, Brooklyn, NY, Photo: Hazel Hankin Photography, Ford Foundation Annual Report 2004 - 1 slide
  - Hazel Hankin Photo: Girl in Window, TIF file, undated; CDRW (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Democratic Republic of the Congo, LeMoyne, 2003-2005; Prints (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - 1075 Project Quest/Texas Electronic Engineering Extension (TEEX) - Annual Report - Photos: Stephen Shames, 1996 July 28; 11 contact sheets, 1 black/white 8x10 print (Box 6, Folder 53)
    San Antonio, TX - 96483 1994
  - 1076 Project Uhuru: Family Resource Coalition - Annual Report - Photos: Stephen Shames, 1996 August 16; 7 contact sheets (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - 1077 Texas Interfaith/Industrial Areas Foundation (TIAF) - Annual Report - Photos: Stephen Shames, 1994 July 26; 9 Contact Sheets (Box 6, Folder 55)
    Flagstaff, Arizona 96487 1994
  - 1078 Families and Work Institute UP - Photos: Stephen Shames, 1994 August 9; 7 Contact Sheets (Box 6, Folder 56)
    New York, NY - 96768 1994 - The Fatherhood Project, Cardinal Spellman Head Start Center on the Lower East Side
  - 1079 The National Institute for Responsible Fatherhood and Family Development UP - Photos: Stephen Shames, 1994 August; 22 Contact Sheets (Box 6, Folder 57)
    Cleveland, Ohio 96686 1994
  - 1080 The National Training and Information Center UP - Photos: Stephen Shames, 1994 September 2; 4 Contact Sheets (Box 6, Folder 58)
    Chicago, IL - 97611
  - 1081 The Rocky Mount/Edgecombe Development Corporation UP - Photos: Stephen Shames, 1994 August 11; 5 Contact Sheets (Box 6, Folder 59)
    Rocky Mount, NC 96952
  - 1082 Warren Community Improvement Association UP - Photos: Stephen Shames, 1994 August 2; 7 Contact Sheets (Box 7, Folder 60)
    Detroit, MI - 96485 Warren/Corner Development Coalition (W/CDC) 1994
  - 1083 Wilson Community Improvement Association UP - Photos: Stephen Shames, 1994 August 11; 9 Contact Sheets (Box 7, Folder 61)
    Wilson, NC 96950 1994
  - 1084 Yonkers "Scatter Site" Housing Project UP - Photos: Stephen Shames, 1994 August 7; 9 contact sheets (Box 7, Folder 62)
    Yonkers, NY 96769 1994
  - 1085 Indonesian Reception Ford Foundation - Photos: Tracey Litt, 1996 October 17; 5 negative strips, 41 BW 4x6photos, 5 contact sheets (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - 1086 On Loan at India Office - Pradan Grantee, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    Signed out to Jane Rosser - "Will return 7/8/1998"
  - 1087 Vijay Mahajan - Winter Report 1997 - Photos: Tracey Litt, 1996; 4 contact sheets, 1 Black/White 8x10 print (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - 1088 Brazil Nut Harvest - Spring Report 1997 - Photos: Carlos Carvalho, 4 color prints, 4B/W Xerox's, 11 B/W prints, 8 contact sheets (Box 7, Folder 66)
    Some prints captioned: Brazil, Combu Island, Spring Report 1997
  - 1089 Natalie Goldring, British American Security Information Council (BASIC), Annual Report 1996 - Photos: Richard Bloom, 1997; 2 B/W prints, 1 contact sheet (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - 1090 Rebecca Adamson, First Nations Development Institute - Photos: Kevin Eilbeck, 1997; 10 B/W prints, 10 contact sheets (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - 1091 District 6 Museum, South Africa - Spring Report 1997 - Photos: Louise Gubb, 35 B/W prints, 8 contact sheets (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - 1092 Porgy and Bess - Photo Reproduction, undated; 4 B/W 4x6 prints, 2 internegatives (Box 7, Folder 70)
    Prints from the Van Damm Collection, NYPL - 1935 Theatre Guild Production New York
  - 1093 GPP3 - Annual Report 1995 - ML Working Files, 4 B/W 8x10 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - 1094 Eastern Shore of Virginia - Spring Report 1997 - Photos: Kirk Condyles, 13 B/W 8x10 prints, 25 contact sheets (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - 1095 Airplanes - Photo: R. Schumacher, 1995; 1 B/W 8x10 print; Folder's original title: 1095 Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - 1096 Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) - Meet the Composer, City Lore, Inc. (Both NYC) - Ping Chong and Company, 1997 February (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - 1097 On Loan - Rio De Janeiro Offices Photographs, 1998 September 25; 1 BW Print - Box 41990, File 1096 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - 1098 Ford/Chile Office - Photos: Helen Hughes, 1994-1997; 9 B/W 8x10 prints, 3 color 8x10prints, 1 color 3x5 print (Box 8, Folder 76)
    1995 Annual Report, Winter Report 1997
  - 1099 Ford/New Delhi, India - Annual Report 1996, 7 B/W 8x10, 1 B/W 5x7, 1 internegative (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - 1100 United Nations Photos, 1990-1996; 17 B/W 8x10 prints (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - 1101 Ford/Mexico City Office - Annual Report 1996, 1996-1997; 16 B/W 5x7 prints, 8 color 4x6 prints, 4 B/W 5x7 color prints (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - 1102 Ford/Windhoek, South Africa Office - 1997 Reports - Photos: Shawn Benjamin, 1996-1997; 5 4x6 color prints, 8 color 4x6 prints, 4 B/W 5x7 color prints, correspondence (Box 8, Folder 80)
    Swearing-in of Mamphela Ramphele as Vice-Chancellor of the University of Cape Town, South Africa, 1996
  - 1103 Russia Office, 1996; 6 B/W 5x7 photos, negatives (Box 8, Folder 81)